Julien GUERINET

• Ottawa, ON, Canada

♦ https://jguerinet.com
♦ https://github.com/jguerinet
♦ https://linkedin.com/in/jguerinet
♦ http

PROFILE

Accomplished Android developer with 6 years of demonstrated experience seeking to continuously improve my skills and knowledge of the platform. Beginner iOS developer eager for the opportunity to expand my experience. Excellent communication and social skills and two years of management experience. Fluent in both English and French, conversational Spanish and Italian. French citizen living as a permanent resident in Ottawa.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Extensive experience in a variety of languages and platforms, including:
 - o Java (8 years)
 - o Git (8 years)
 - Android (6 years)
 - Kotlin (2 years)
 - Swift (1 year)
- Introductory-level proficiency in: iOS, Objective-C, TypeScript
- Completed courses in digital system design, robotics, hardware description languages, computer organization and architecture, software engineering practices, algorithms, and telecommunication networks.
- Very familiar with the SCRUM agile development methodology.
- Actively comment my code through extensive use of Javadocs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead, Development – Ottawa mHealth at Ottawa Hospital Research Institute *Ottawa, ON, CANADA (February 2017 – January 2019)*

- Managed the program's entire development team, comprised of six developers (Android, iOS, web, and QA).
- Held weekly meetings with development team to set project goals and get updates on deliverables.
- Followed the SCRUM agile methodology with three week sprints for rapid turnarounds when needed and continuous deployment of new features on all platforms.
- Regularly met with clients in order to gather their technical requirements, propose solutions, determine budgets, and establish timelines.
- Met with the management team of Ottawa mHealth weekly in order to decide on future projects and new directions for current projects.
- Continued to contribute actively to both the Android and iOS codebases (primarily Android).

Head of Mobile Development - Ottawa mHealth at Ottawa Hospital Research Institute

Ottawa, ON, CANADA (April 2016 – January 2017)

- Oversaw the mobile development of all projects taken on by Ottawa mHealth.
- Managed the iOS and Android developers by guiding their work efforts, setting timelines, ensuring that deliverables were being met, and providing any resources necessary.

Lead Mobile Developer – Ottawa mHealth at Hospital Research Institute

Ottawa, ON, CANADA (September 2015 – March 2016)

- Developed multiple apps on both the Android and iOS platforms (primarily Android).
- Improved and maintained CANImmunize Android.

Julien GUERINET

• Ottawa, ON, Canada

- ♦ https://jguerinet.com
 ♦ https://github.com/jguerinet
 ♦ https://linkedin.com/in/jguerinet
 ♦ http
 - Worked on multiple other projects including a stroke rehabilitation platform, a food diary app for patients with renal failure, a helper app for transplant patients (<u>SafeLiving</u>), and a clinical decision guidelines app (<u>The Ottawa Rules</u>).

Android Developer – AdForum Worldwide Summit

Remote (March 2014 – PRESENT)

- Responsible for the entire Android version of the AdForum Worldwide Summit App.
- Currently tasked with maintaining the app and implementing any new features requested.

Lead Mobile Developer - Sigvaria Mobile Technologies Inc.

Montreal, QC, CANADA (January 2013 – August 2015)

- Lead of all Android projects, most notably <u>CANImmunize</u>, which was built from scratch and released during this time and is now used by over 250 000 Canadians nationwide.
- Regularly met with clients, drafted documentation, presented prototypes, and provided updates on the final products.

EDUCATION

McGill University: Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering

Montreal, QC, CANADA (September 2010 – December 2014)

OTHER PROJECTS

 (January 2014 – Present) Developed the unofficial open-sourced McGill app known as <u>MyMartlet</u> with other McGill University students in the role of project manager and lead Android developer. The Android version app was released in September 2014 and I am still actively maintaining this app.

PUBLICATIONS

Pugliese M, Ramsay T, Shamloul R, Mallet K, Zakutney L, Corbett D, Dukelow S, Stotts G, Shamy M, Wilson K, <u>Guerinet J</u>, Dowlatshai D. RecoverNow: A mobile tablet-based therapy platform for early stroke rehabilitation. PLoSOne. 2019. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0210725

Paradis M, Stiell I, Atkinson KM, <u>Guerinet J</u>, Sequeira Y, Salter L, Forster A, Murphy MSQ, Wilson K. Acceptability of a mobile clinical decision tool amongst Emergency Department clinicians: development and evaluation of The Ottawa Rules App. JMIR mHealth and uHealth. Accepted 6 April 2018. doi:10.2196/10263

Pugliese MW, Wilson K, <u>Guerinet J</u>, Atkinson KM, Mallet KH, Shamloul R, Zakutney L, Corbett D, Dowlatshahi D. Mobile Tablet-Based Stroke Rehabilitation: Using mHealth Technology to Improve Access to Early Stroke Rehabilitation. International Journal of Interactive Mobile Technologies. 2017; 11(1): 148-157. doi:10.3991/ijim.v11i1.6234

Imtiaz R, Atkinson K, <u>Guerinet J</u>, Wilson K, Zimmerman D. A Pilot Study of OkKidney, a Phosphate Counting Application in Patients on Peritoneal Dialysis. Peritoneal Dialysis International. 37(6):613-618. doi: 10.3747/pdi.2017.00050

Bell C, <u>Guerinet J</u>, Atkinson KM, Wilson K. Feasibility and limitations of vaccine two-dimensional barcoding using mobile devices. Journal of Medical Internet Research. 2016. 18(6):e143. doi: 10.2196/jmir.5591